Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Plantinga, Carl	Affective Incongruity and The Thin Red Line	"affect and film; emotion and film; film criticism; film interpretation; Malick; The Thin Red Line"		Most films, most of the time, are affectively unified. What I call synesthetic affects are orchestrated in an attempt to provide a holistic affective experience congruent with the film's unfolding narrative and thematic concerns. Yet Terrence Malick's The Thin Red Line elicits contradictory or incongruent affects, such incongruence neither being justified by genre conventions, excess, irony, nor stumbled upon through incompetence. The Thin Red Line elicits incongruent emotions for the purposes of generating an experience of rumination and wonder. The study of such incongruent emotions, still in its infancy, raises important methodological issues about the study of mixed emotions and the conventions for mixing affects in the cinema.
