Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Milani, Raffaele	The prioritization of anaphora and the affinities among the arts	"Aesthetics; Comparativistics; Philosophy; Poetics; Form"		In the face of the most recent developments in digital and visual art, the Internet, the latest frontiers and currents, the new languages and technologies, Souriau's schema does not work, but his reflections on the aesthetic notions of instauration and skeuopoetics do, and they pertain both to classical painting and to future perspectives. In fact, we note strong connections with research that the philosopher had had conducted on feelings, relations, forms, and processes, in terms of synaesthesia and structural correspondences. On the basis of his thinking, we can still argue the importance of these concepts and these relations as they relate to physical and phenomenal existence, to materiality and transcendence: a conceptual and imaginative universal that is considered to be eternal. Art is seen as the producer of things capable of performing actions that are purely physical. He makes this claim because these actions expressly and intentionally create things whose existence is their sole purpose.
