Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Naumer, Marcus J.; van den Bosch, Jasper J. F."	Touching Sounds: Thalamocortical Plasticity and the Neural Basis of Multisensory Integration		AUDITORY ASSOCIATION CORTEX	"Naumer MJ, van den Bosch JJF. Touching sounds: thalamocortical plasticity and the neural basis of multisensory integration. J Neurophysiol 102: 7-8, 2009. First published April 29, 2009; doi: 10.1152/jn.00209.2009. To date, noninvasive neuroimaging research on multisensory perception has focused on cortical activations. In a series of elegant functional magnetic resonance imaging experiments, Beauchamp and Ro recently investigated altered cortical activations associated with acquired sound-touch synesthesia resulting from a thalamic lesion. Their findings highlight the important role of intact thalamocortical projections for preventing illusory crossmodal perception and for underlying reliable multisensory integration."
