Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Beugnet, Martine	Cinema and sensation: Contemporary French film and cinematic corporeality	"cinema and the senses : theory and practice; contemporary French cinema; corporeality in film; embodied thought; film aesthetics and sensation; film and embodiment; synaesthesia in film"		One of the most fascinating phenomena in contemporary art cinema is the re-emergence of a corporeal cinema, that is, of filmmaking practices (and, by extension, of theoretical approaches) that give precedence to cinema as the medium of the senses. This article thus explores trends of filmmaking and film theorizing where the experience of cinema is conceived as a unique combination of sensation and thought, of affect and reflection. It argues that, reconnecting with a certain tradition of French film theory in particular, contemporary French cinema offers a point in case: a large collection of recently released French films typify this willingness to explore cinema's unique capacity to move us both viscerally and intellectually. In turn, the article suggests that Such films, envisaged as Forms of embodied thought, offer alternative ways, beyond that of mere appropriation and consumption, of envisaging he relationship of subjects to art, and, by extension, of subjects to objective world.
