Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Brewis, S.; Baguley, D. M."	Management of tinnitus induced by brainstern and cerebellar infarction associated with complications of cerebello-pontine angle surgery	"tinnitus; hearing aid; infarction; brainstem"	REORGANIZATION	Following surgery in the USA in 1992 to remove a large right cerebello-pontine angle turnout, a 39-year-old woman developed severe brainstem and cerebellar infarction. This left her with severe visual impairment and ataxia. She became able to communicate by means of an adapted finger-spelling alphabet. She had total hearing loss in the right ear and a mild to moderately severe sensorineural hearing loss in the left ear, and severe finnitus heard throughout the head. Additionally, she experienced hypersensitivity to sound above normal conversational levels, which evoked a synaesthetic feeling of coldness across her upper torso. Previous linear analogue hearing aid fitting had not been beneficial for either hearing or tinnitus. Careful fitting of a digital hearing aid, together with tinnitus counselling, inhibited the patient's tinnitus to 25 per cent of its former intensity after a six month acclimatisation period, and improved communication.
