Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Lee, Angela M.	Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response and the Disability Resource Center: An Exploratory Review of Student Perceptions	"autonomous sensory meridian responses; ASMR; disability resource center; student perceptions"		Researchers have examined autonomous sensory meridian responses (ASMRs) focusing on known experiencers and the nuances surrounding those occurrences. This exploratory study was developed in response to existing ASMR research focusing on individuals who were not necessarily known ASMR experiencers. My goal was to better understand whether these synesthesial responses affected a student's education. There were no statistical differences among participants. However, more students responded that they experienced a reaction to specific sounds but did not believe they experienced ASMR. In open-ended responses, the primary themes surrounded empathy, resources, and negative perceptions as the response to the impact of ASMR on education and benefits offered through disability resource center (DRC).
