Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Benitez-Burraco, Antonio; Progovac, Ljiljana"	Language evolution: examining the link between cross-modality and aggression through the lens of disorders	"language evolution; cognitive disorders; self-domestication; metaphoricity and cross-modality; aggression and derogatory language; inhibition; disinhibition"	"GRAPHEME-COLOR SYNAESTHESIA; AUTISM SPECTRUM DISORDERS; ATYPICAL SENSORY SENSITIVITY; TOURETTE-SYNDROME; BASAL GANGLIA; SELF-DOMESTICATION; INDIVIDUAL-DIFFERENCES; FUNCTIONAL-ANATOMY; HUMAN BRAIN; SCHIZOPHRENIA"	We demonstrate how two linguistic phenomena, figurative language (implicating cross-modality) and derogatory language (implicating aggression), both demand a precise degree of (dis)inhibition in the same cortico-subcortical brain circuits, in particular cortico-striatal networks, whose connectivity has been significantly enhanced in recent evolution. We examine four cognitive disorders/conditions that exhibit abnormal patterns of (dis)inhibition in these networks: schizophrenia (SZ), autism spectrum disorder (ASD), synaesthesia and Tourette's syndrome (TS), with the goal of understanding why the two phenomena altered reactive aggression and altered cross-modality cluster together in these disorders. Our proposal is that enhanced cross-modality (necessary to support language, in particular metaphoricity) was a result, partly a side-effect, of self-domestication (SD). SD targeted the taming of reactive aggression, but reactive impulses are controlled by the same cortico-subcortical networks that are implicated in cross-modality. We further add that this biological process of SD did not act alone, but was engaged in an intense feedback loop with the cultural emergence of early forms of language/grammar, whose high degree of raw metaphoricity and verbal aggression also contributed to increased brain connectivity and cortical control. Consequently, in conjunction with linguistic expressions serving as approximations/'fossils' of the earliest stages of language, these cognitive disorders/conditions serve as confident proxies of brain changes in language evolution, helping us reconstruct certain crucial aspects of early prehistoric languages and cognition, as well as shed new light on the nature of the disorders. This article is part of the theme issue 'Reconstructing prehistoric languages'.
