Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Uno, Kyuto; Asano, Michiko; Yokosawa, Kazuhiko"	Consistency of synesthetic association varies with grapheme familiarity: A longitudinal study of grapheme-color synesthesia	"Synesthesia; Grapheme-color synesthesia; Consistency; Familiarity"		Grapheme-color synesthesia is a condition in which the visual perception of letters or numbers induces a specific color sensation. The consistency of grapheme-color association has been considered as a fundamental characteristic of synesthesia. However, recent studies have indicated that this association can change across the adult lifespan, and it has become necessary to investigate the factors behind the changes within each synesthete. We conducted a longitudinal study of Japanese adult synesthetes to investigate long-term (5?8 years) changes in color responses to 300 graphemes (alphanumeric and Japanese characters). Graphemes with lower longterm consistency of synesthetic association also tended to have lower short-term consistency, indicating that grapheme-color association?s consistency is determined for each grapheme. Further, less familiar graphemes had less consistent associations with their synesthetic colors. These findings suggest that a stronger grapheme-color association is formed for more familiar graphemes, leading to the consolidation of synesthetic color for such graphemes.
