Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Perilli, Lorenzo	Synaesthesia. Clues of Archaism in the Conception of Sight and Hearing of the Hippocratic Collection	"Hippocratic collection; (sic); sight; hearing; synaesthesia; Upanishad; breath-soul; perception; thought"		There are some ideas of perception, deeply rooted in the archaic understanding of man and its environment, clues of which can still be seen in some writings of the Hippocratic collection, such as Regimen, Diseases of Women, and Fleshes. These clues suggest synaesthesia as a notion for the understanding of the apparently different perceptions, assuming an interchangeability in the activity of sensory organs. A physical, immediate relationship between the perceiving body and the objects perceived, implies a direct connection with internal organs usually located in the belly and the bowels, while perceptions move all around the body together with the breath-soul. It is by way of the breath, of inspiration and expiration, that the bodily organs active in seeing and hearing appropriate the external world and become one and the same thing with it. Revealing similiarities with the ancient Vedic texts of the Upanishads are also mentioned.
