Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Galazhinskiy, Eduard, V; Kabrin, Valery, I"	The Prospect of the Development of a Creative Personality of a Trans-Professional in the Conditions of Changes in the Scientific and Educational Paradigm of the University	"holodynamics; noodynamic; transcommunication; trans-professional; imaginative methods; creative leadership"	LEADERSHIP	"The article presents a project for the development of a creative personality of a trans-professional in the context of education based on the transcommunicative paradigm. The article indicates the crisis of higher education in the transition to a post-industrial society. A social request for a creative person with a trans-professional outlook contradicts formal education, which leads to the degradation of creative and personal dimensions of an individual. The transdisciplinary development of modem sciences and the new scientific worldview lead to a new synthesis of the holodynamic and noodynamic paradigms as the basis for the synthesis of natural and human sciences in education and research projects. In this context, a new image of a university is being formed as a source of a new transcommunicative culture and a trans-professional worldview. The generalization of the latest results of the studies of quantum holodynamics in physics and imaginative neurodynamics in psychology makes it possible to build new ecologically relevant models of transdisciplinary educational programs and scientific and technological solutions. On the basis of the synthesis of the holodynamic and noodynamic paradigms, the authors propose a conceptual and phenomenological scheme of transcommunication, in which the qualities of a trans-professional creative personality are harmoniously revealed and developed. The article shows that a person masters the contexts of life, education and science with multiple scales that evoke four significant transcommunicative culture formations: (1) moments of spontaneous meetings, at which stress-trans-formation reveals something new in the unknown thus creating new trans-meanings; (2) transcommunicative meaningful situations, in which, thanks to syntony and synesthesia, the ability to mutual synchronous feedback arises. (3) transcommunicative environments, in which intuitive insight manifests itself in contact; creative originality of discourse occurs in conversations; ingenious problem solving happens in discussion; delicate wisdom occurs in relationships; (4) in transcommunicative axiological worlds (of personalities, groups, teams), a proactive selective search for an individual configuration of relations is implemented for optimal creative self-realization. It has been established that active participation in these processes of mastering a transcommunicative culture develops creative leadership as a basic competence of a trans-professional personality. Thus, the transcommunicative paradigm organically combines the development of creative and communicative features of a personality in scientific and educational projects of a university, which in traditional approaches hardly correlate."
