Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Haneef, M. Shuaib Mohamed	Multimodal social semiotic analysis of Delhi rape conviction news in 2013 in CNN IBN website	"Multimodality; affect; hypermodality; Halliday's systemic functional linguistics; Delhi gang rape case"		Performative acts of reading in websites are defined by interactivity which constitutes a site of action and signs in cyberspace. The interactive potential in websites is further augmented through multimodal representations of content. Multimodality hinges on synaesthetic combinations of multiple modes such as orality, writing, visuality and sound. This paper seeks to examine the multimodal representations of discourses surrounding the news of death sentence awarded to four convicts involved in Delhi gang rape and murder of Nirbhaya in CNN IBN news website. Furthermore, it adopts an approach to locate affective forces that characterise the multimodal text concerning the macro-theme of the news through mediated discourses of affect.
