Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Alonso, Cristina Parreno	Tectonics of Perception: Representation of Atmospheres Through Synesthetic Notation			Drawing a parallelism with cognitive synesthesia, an automatic phenomenon by which certain individuals experience cross pairings of at least two sensory organs, this essay defines the term synesthetic notation as a system of representation by which the rules of two discrete notation systems are voluntary interchanged. An array of students' projects illustrates synesthetic notation as particularly instrumental in the representation of atmospheres. Each project represents one aspect of the environment giving over its experiential condition, privileging instead the dynamic character of the generated artifacts and their transformative capacity in the ability to suggest new alternative realities.
