Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Ginter, Anna	SOME REMARKS ON THE TRANSLATION OF RUSSIAN SYNAESTHETIC METAPHORS INTO POLISH	"synaesthesia; synaesthetic metaphor; translation; conventional metaphor; creative metaphor; Vladimir Nabokov"		The present paper is devoted to the analysis of synaesthetic metaphors in the Russian language from the perspective of their translation into Polish. The theoretical discussion is supported by the analysis of the translation of two types of synaesthetic metaphors - conventional and creative. As it has been shown, the behaviour of synaesthetic metaphors in translation is similar to that of other metaphors. In conventional metaphors historically close languages, such as Russian and Polish, often share similar cross-modal mappings, which make it possible to find a corresponding metaphor. In the case of creative synaesthetic metaphors, a word-by-word translation seem to be the most successful strategy. The translators, however, try to find more creative solution by modifying the synaesthetic association in the target language text.
