Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Krylova, Alexandra, V	The New Ideology of Musical Theater and its Manifestation in the Works of Heiner Goebbels	"Heiner Goebbels; musical theater computer technologies; contemporary opera; experimental musical theater; synthesis of the arts"		The article analyzes the artistic legacy of the outstanding reformer of contemporary musical theater - producer, musician, composer and theatrical theorist Heiner Goebbels. The cardinal difference of his diversified works from the traditional model of opera theatre makes it possible to speak of a new theatrical ideology, of which Goebbels shows himself to be an adept. On the basis of numerous interviews with the composer and his personal utterances about his art, the article examines a set of peculiarities which characterize his musical-theatrical works in light of the innovative endeavors of the authorial aesthetics of musical theatre. A big role in its formation has been played by contemporary musical-theatrical technical resources, which have made it possible to achieve on the basis of digital computer technologies to achieve a new high-quality level of synthesis of the arts and elements which unite on a conceptual artistic platform sound, text, color, light, fire, water, scents, depictions, video projections and other things. The aim of this is to expand the possibilities of impact on the synesthetic foundations of human perception. Each component of the indicated synthesis is interpreted by the composer as independent informational message. Being a true artist of the postmodern era, Goebbels presents the musical performance as a counterpoint of a number of diverse texts. The high level of density of the informational plane of theatrical performance also necessitates a new perspective of the process of communication with the viewer, who does not interpret the meanings grounded by the author, but to a great degree plays the role of its creator. A number of aforementioned and other particularities of Goebbels' musical theater is examined in the article on the basis of the opera Landschaft mit entfernten Verwandten [Landscape with Distant Relatives].
