Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Levisen, Carsten	Dark, but Danish: Ethnopragmatic perspectives on black humor	"ethnopragmatics; Danish semantics; sort humor; black humor; synesthetic humor metaphor"	"AUSTRALIAN ENGLISH; KILIVILA; JOKE"	This paper explores sort humor 'black humor', a key concept in Danish conversational humor. Sort forms part of a larger class of Danish synesthetic humor metaphors that includes other categories such as tor 'dry', syg 'sick', and fed 'fat'. Taking an ethnopragmatic perspective on humor discourse, it is argued that such constructs function as a local catalogue for socially recognized laughing practices. The aim of the paper is to provide a semantic explication for sort humor and explore the discursive practices associated with the concept. From a comparative perspective, it is demonstrated that the Danish conceptualization of blackness differs from that of l'humour noir, a category of French surrealism, and English black humor with its off-limit topics such as death and handicap. In Danish discourse, sort humor has come to stand for a practice of collaborative jocular non-sense making. It is further argued that the main function of sort humor is to establish or enhance a feeling of groupy togetherness.
