Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Li, Rui; Feng, Anran; Zhang, Linghao; Chen, Yingjie Victor"	Light interaction in the application of home water purification system	"Emotion interaction; User experience; Light application; Design method"	"SYNAESTHESIA; PEOPLE; COLOR"	Application of lighting effect into water purifying systems was studied to achieve the emotional interaction between users and products. This study involves two groups of experiments. First, the water quality scale corresponding to colours was scored by each subject, and then the colours were classified. Second, the impacts of lighting effect on heart rate, skin temperature, skin electrical signal, and other psychological indices in emotion experiments were studied, which validate that light effect plays a non-negligible role in the emotions of the subjects. By collecting System Usability Scale (SUS) scores, average heart rate, average skin temperature, and skin electrical signal, we compared the results before and after the addition of lighting effect, and validated the influences of lighting effect on human emotions. This study theoretically underlies the application of lighting effect into smart home.
