Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Coe, Megan Varvir	Musicality of Language and Corporeal Writing in La Tragedie de Salome (1907)	"Florent Schmitt; Loie Fuller; Salome; symbolism; musicality"		This article explores the seemingly paradoxical role of dance when the aesthetics of a literary movement such as Symbolism aspires to a wordless genrea paradox articulated by Stephane Mallarme in his famous coinage corporeal writing. I propose a reevaluation of Symbolist thought on the musicality of language as a possible means of reconciling the disparity between pure words and pure movement. A Symbolist conception of the arts as analogous to one another allowed for poetic writing, through the intervening medium of sound, to approach dance through an integration of meaning and movement. Using the ballet-pantomime La Tragedie de Salome (1907) as a case study, I argue that Florent Schmitt's score transfers the essence of language into music that, when accompanied by the synesthetic performance of Loie Fuller, evoked the multisensory theatrical experience to which Symbolist dramaturgy aspired.
