Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Roncero Palomar, Ricardo	SYNESTHESIA AND RHYTHM. THE ROAD TO ABSOLUTE CINEMA	"Absolute cinema; visual music; historical avant-garde; synesthesia; organ color; animation cinema; abstract cinema"	COLOR	Absolute cinema, developed during the historical avant-garde, continued with a long artistic tradition that linked to musical with visual experience. Due to cinema as medium of expression, these filmmakers were able to work with the moving image to develop concepts such as rhythm, also with more complex figures than the colored spots that other devices could create at that time. This study starts with the published texts in 1704 by Newton about color, and provides an overview of those artistic highlights that link image and sound, and which creates the origins of absolute cinema. The connections and equivalences between the visual and sound experiences used by these filmmakers are also studied in order to know if there was a continuous line with the origins of these studies or if there was a rupture and other later investigations were able to have more repercussion in their works.
