Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Sanz Garcia, Laura	MUSIC AND GARDENS IN GRANADA. DEBUSSY AND FORESTIER'S FRENCH MARK IN SPANISH ARTISTIC CREATION	"Claude Debussy; J.C.N. Forestier; musical impressionism; landscape architecture; synesthesia; cultural relationships Spain-France; Hispano-Arabic gardens; Granada; Manuel de Falla; Javier de Winthuysen"		This article aims to delve into the aspects that connect both Spanish and French musicians and landscapers' works around the cultural image of Spain, as well as the importance of gardens in the visual inspiration of impressionist music. For that purpose, the text presents an analysis of the thematic and stylistic parallelisms between two outstanding French artists, the composer Claude Debussy and the landscape architect Jean-Claude Nicolas Forestier, in relation to the Arab-Andalusian exotism and, more specifically, to the gardens of Granada. To their common interest in representing the authentic essence of all that is Spanish, one should add the same avant-garde intention and a series of themes that translate into artistic terms their personal interpretation of Al-Andalus. On the other hand, the influence exercised by Debussy and Forestier on the Spanish artists - such as Falla and Javier de Winthuysen-, relates France once more to the development of modern art and music in Spain. This interdisciplinary analysis reveals a common sensibility in the axis France Spain and between two artistic disciplines apparently uneven as music and gardening. Debussy and Forestier, as well as their Spanish disciples, intend to overcome the romantic images of Spain, using the Hispano-Arabic cliche to update their respective artistic languages, in music and landscape architecture, in the transition to the 20th century.
