Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Kanaya, Shoko; Kariya, Kenji; Fujisaki, Waka"	Cross-Modal Correspondence Among Vision, Audition, and Touch in Natural Objects: An Investigation of the Perceptual Properties of Wood	"Cross-modal correspondence; Perceptual properties of wood; Vision; Audition; Touch; Natural objects"	"SPEEDED CLASSIFICATION; SOUND; SYNAESTHESIA; SIMILARITY; COLOR; SIZE"	"Certain systematic relationships are often assumed between information conveyed from multiple sensory modalities; for instance, a small figure and a high pitch may be perceived as more harmonious. This phenomenon, termed cross-modal correspondence, may result from correlations between multi-sensory signals learned in daily experience of the natural environment. If so, we would observe cross-modal correspondences not only in the perception of artificial stimuli but also in perception of natural objects. To test this hypothesis, we reanalyzed data collected previously in our laboratory examining perceptions of the material properties of wood using vision, audition, and touch. We compared participant evaluations of three perceptual properties (surface brightness, sharpness of sound, and smoothness) of the wood blocks obtained separately via vision, audition, and touch. Significant positive correlations were identified for all properties in the audition-touch comparison, and for two of the three properties regarding in the vision-touch comparison. By contrast, no properties exhibited significant positive correlations in the vision-audition comparison. These results suggest that we learn correlations between multi-sensory signals through experience; however, the strength of this statistical learning is apparently dependent on the particular combination of sensory modalities involved."
