Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Hagtvedt, Henrik; Brasel, S. Adam"	Cross-Modal Communication: Sound Frequency Influences Consumer Responses to Color Lightness	"color; sound; aesthetics; cross-modal correspondence; sensory marketing"	"PERCEPTION; AUTOMATICITY; ATTENTION; OBJECTS; TASTE"	"This research demonstrates that the synesthetic cross-modal correspondence between sound frequency and color lightness can guide visual attention: high-frequency (low-frequency) sounds guide visual attention toward light-colored (dark-colored) objects. Three eye-tracking studies indicate that this influence is automatic; it arises without goals or conscious awareness, it seems to take precedence over the influence from a simultaneously occurring semantic correspondence, and it even operates despite explicit instructions to the contrary. Two additional studies highlight the potential role for this influence in marketing contexts. In Study 4, the audio frequency in a soundtrack guides visual attention in a commercial, as evidenced by recall of marketing messages. In Study 5, customers in a supermarket exposed to high-frequency (vs. low-frequency) music are more likely to purchase products from a shelf with light (vs. dark) decor."
