Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Triarhou, Lazaros C.	Neuromusicology or Musiconeurology? Omni-art in Alexander Scriabin as a Fount of Ideas	"neuroaesthetics; synaesthetics; integrative aesthetics; composers; pianists"		Science can uncover neural mechanisms by looking at the work of artists. The ingenuity of a titan of classical music, the Russian composer Alexander Scriabin (1872-1915), in combining all the sensory modalities into a polyphony of aesthetical experience, and his creation of a chord based on fourths rather than the conventional thirds are proposed as putative points of departure for insight, in future studies, into the neural processes that underlie the perception of beauty, individually or universally. Scriabin's Omni-art was a new synthesis of music, philosophy and religion, and a new aesthetic language, a unification of music, vision, olfaction, drama, poetry, dance, image, and conceptualization, all governed by logic, in the quest for the integrative action of the human mind toward a higher reality of which music is only a component.
