Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Gomez Moral, Alba	Multidisciplinary project Synaesthesia: hallucinate. Learning experience	"synaesthesia; multidisciplinary project; methodology bases on tasks; Spanish Language and Literature"		This paper is based on a learning experience wich was made focused on synaesthesia. Apart from it rhetorical condition, synaesthesia consist of a neurological anomaly that causes a connection between different senses. This double approach - linguistic and physiological-is in the base of a multidisciplinary project carried out by students of the subjects of Sciences and Spanish Language and Literature.
