Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Teric, Marijana	DEVELOPMENT OF MONTENEGRIN LITERATURE FOR CHILDREN AND YOUTH	"Montenegrin poetry for children and youth; terminology designations; modern poetic texts; sound-expressive features; didactic function"		In this paper, the author discusses the development of children's literature in Montenegro with special emphasis on the poetic texts of the authors included by Slobodan Vukanovic in his Anthology of Montenegrin Poetry for Children and Teenagers. Bearing in mind the thematic motif diversity of the book, the Anthology shows the way in which poets form their poetic visions and send them to their audience. Simplicity, witty point, sound-expressive features, colour synaesthesia, are just some of the peculiarities of diverse poetic universe, which is constituted in the mind of each child. Anthology shows a hint of the new themes as well, brand-new views of the world of poetry for children in which we recognize pedagogical-didactic component as well.
