Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Seiryte, Aurelija; Rusconi, Elena"	The Empathy Quotient (EQ) predicts perceived strength of bodily illusions and illusion-related sensations of pain	"Empathy Quotient; Rubber Hand Illusion; Mirror-touch synaesthesia; Illusory pain; Extreme Female Brain"	"RUBBER HAND ILLUSION; VISION-TOUCH SYNAESTHESIA; SEX-DIFFERENCES; SELF; FEEL; REPRESENTATIONS; AUTISM; BRAIN; EXTREME; ANXIETY"	In this study we test the possible implications of high empathising skills on bodily self-other distinction by measuring the strength of a body ownership illusion and a related experience of illusory pain. One-hundred adult participants completed the Empathy Quotient (EQ) questionnaire. Twenty participants from the top quintile and 20 participants from the bottom quintile of the EQ distribution took part in a laboratory experiment. In the experiment, a classical Rubber Hand Illusion (RHI) was induced followed by the presentation of a series of painful stimuli to the rubber hand. Participants were asked to self-rate the strength of their subjective experience of the RHI and of the illusory pain. A proprioceptive location judgment on the position of the hidden hand was also required before and after RHI induction, to record drifts towards the rubber hand. We found a significant difference between high- and low-empathy participants in RHI and pain score. The EQ was not related with the proprioceptive location judgement drift. It thus appears to be a better predictor of subjective ownership feelings and phenomenological self-other merging than of the behavioural components of bodily illusions. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
