Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Kent, Adam	CORRAL, CAFE, AND CONCERT HALL: ENRIQUE GRANADOS'S EL FANDANGO DE CANDIL AND MANUEL DE FALLA'S  DANZA DE LA MOLINERA	"Falla; Albeniz; Granados; Turina; folkloricism; synesthesia; El sombrero de tres picos; Goyescas"		The Fandango has been an internationally recognized trope in European classical music since the early eighteenth century. Spanish-born and Hispanicized composers such as Domenico Scarlatti, Antonio Soler, and Luigi Boccherini created a tradition of the fandango as a virtuoso keyboard or chamber music work, featuring increasingly frenzied variations over a simple harmonic formula, while Mozart famously alluded to the genre as a courtly dance in the third act of his Marriage of Figaro. Enrique Granados and Manuel de Falla, Spanish nationalist composers of the early twentieth century, treated the Fandango to postromantic and impressionistic harmonic vocabulary and the outlines of sonata form. In El fandango del candil from his Goyescas suite for solo piano, Granados employs a full arsenal of late-nineteenth century piano techniques, much as Falla utilizes the resources of the Debussyian orchestra in the Danza de la molinera from the ballet El sombrero de tres picos. My paper examines the idiosyncratic ways these composers employ contemporary mainstream compositional approaches to evoke the earthy spirit of the dance's folkloric origins.
