Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"McCarthy, J. Daniel; Caplovitz, Gideon Paul"	Color synesthesia improves color but impairs motion perception		"GRAPHEME-COLOR; FORM"	A recent study showed that color synesthetes have increased color sensitivity but impaired motion perception. This is exciting because little research has examined how synesthesia affects basic perceptual processes outside the context of synesthetic experiences. The results suggest that synesthesia broadly impacts perception with greater neural implications than previously considered.
