Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Dykema, Amanda	Embodied Knowledges: Synesthesia and the Archive in Monique Truong's Bitter in the Mouth			Monique Truong's novel Bitter in the Mouth (2010) is the story of a synesthetic Vietnamese American woman who tastes words. Protagonist Linda Hammerick's condition fundamentally structures her epistemological relation to the world: taste-word associations are embodied, catalogued, and performed as Linda seeks the truth of her lost origins. I examine this story of a figure whose bodily difference results in the creation of an embodied archive in order to consider the ways that the archive as an epistemological mode enables a complex negotiation of legacies of violence, trauma, and racial formation. This essay proposes the archive as a figuration that, like race, always appears as disappearing and is thus a generative focus for grappling with contemporary modes of racialization. Bitter in the Mouth theorizes an understanding of the archive that illuminates the centrality of processes of racialization for subject formation and political representation in the contemporary era of (neo)liberal multiculturalism. The novel invites us to ask: what is it about Linda as a synesthetic Asian American woman that requires another mode of memory and recorded knowledge? And in a more theoretical register, what can the form and function of Linda's deeply embodied synesthetic archive reveal about how the discourse of the archive tends to naturalize the link between the body and knowledge? Considering how the functions of race and the archive correlate with one another in US culture and politics, as well as the critical indeterminacy enabled by an embodied archive, this essay seeks to facilitate a rearticulation of difference in our time.
