Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Payne, Renee	THINKING WITH EYES AND HANDS: THE DISCONNECTION OF ART AND LITERATURE IN PORTUGUESE MODERNISM	"Portuguese Futurism; Portuguese Surrealism; Modern Art"		This paper discusses the connection, or rather, the disconnection (the elimination of the designations of genre), between art and literature through a close analysis of two Modernist texts: Saltimbancos by Jose de Almada Negreiros and a paisagem do relOio branco by Mario als a criticism by the author of World War I and the subsequent social deformity it caused. However, the general tone of the narrative (militant and weighted with frustration) remains evident even if the reader does not mages, but it still reflects the goal of the Surrealist movement: to surmount the false reality presented in the Neorealist work of the time period. The story a paisagem do relgio branco succeeds in surpassing reality by making the reader first visualize the displacements and then experience the synesthetic displacement of the text.
