Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Ospina Leon, Juan Sebastian	MOVING STILLS: PORTRAITURE AND SUPERFICIAL TIES IN TWO VISCONTI FILMS	"Neorealism; Melodrama; Luchino Visconti; Southern Question; Italian Studies"		This essay focuses on two films directed by Luchino Visconti, La terra trema (1948) and Rocco e i suoi fratelli (1960) under the light of Southern Question discourses-the subjugation of the South to the North inscribed in the process leading to Italian national affirmation. I address two related issues: the fabrication of southern kinship and social bodies via portraiture, and the latter's relationship to moving images and filmic narrative. Consequently, analyzing film style I question claims of documentary realism in these films, paradigms of neorealist filmmaking, by foregrounding their systematic use of melodramatic conventions. I stress the synesthetic side to melodrama. Spectators look at the screen while in their turn are touched by its moving images. Visconti systematically presents once and again this synesthetic emotional relationship between shots, photographs, and pictures to forward his solution to the Southern Question.
