Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Anderson, Helen	A Distinguishing Skill Art, Language, and Complex Cognition		"INFERIOR TEMPORAL CORTEX; MAGNETIC STIMULATION; ARCUATE FASCICULUS; MOTOR FACILITATION; FUNCTIONAL MRI; BRAIN; EVOLUTION; HUMANS; SYNAESTHESIA; RECOGNITION"	Representational art, when it first emerges in the archaeological record between 30,000-40,000 years ago, is seen as a watershed. It is upheld as one of the defining characteristics that makes us 'human', argued as the 'gold standard' by which cultural modernity is measured and identified and intimately linked with the development of language. In the past decade it has been suggested that the emergence of representational art in prehistory and the concomitance of language are assumptions that may need reviewing. This enquiry looks to recent neuroscientific research, particularly in the area of neural connectivity that may provide some valuable insights between drawing and language. The significance of neural interconnectivity in this enquiry is that the emotional content of our lives may lie at the core of what makes us unique in the animal world and a significant contributory factor to our cognitive evolution, particularly in terms of cultural development.
