Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Chae, Youngjoo	Color appearance shifts depending on surface roughness, illuminants, and physical colors		VISUAL DETERMINATION	Texture is an important synesthetic design element used in textile products. The three-dimensional surface of texture changes the amount and angle of reflected light causing a color appearance change from its original color. In this work, for a wide range of colors, it was quantitatively analyzed how the color appearances change depending on different textures and illumination, such as CIE standard illuminants A, F11, F2, and D65. It was found that strong-textured fabrics (with a surface roughness Ra of 0.46 mm) had larger hue appearance changes and consequent overall color appearance changes from their true colors due to illuminants than non-textured papers (with a surface roughness Ra of 0.03 mm). Between two types of fabrics with different textures of 0.21 and 0.46 mm, however, there was no significant difference in the magnitude of color appearance changes, indicating that the difference in surface roughness greater than 0.43 mm can produce significant differences in color appearance changes induced by illumination. It was also found that the magnitude and direction of color appearance changes under different CIE illuminants differed significantly according to the physical chroma and hue of the surface.
