Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
Kim, Sung-Ill	Conversion of Image into Sound Based on HSI Histogram	"Image-to-sound Conversion; Sound-to-image Conversion; RGB model; HSI model; Histogram"		The final aim of the present study is to develop the intelligent robot, emulating human synesthetic skills which make it possible to associate a color image with a specific sound. This can be done on the basis of the mutual conversion between color image and sound. As a first step of the final goal, this study focused on a basic system using a conversion of color image into sound. This study describes a proposed method to convert color image into sound, based on the likelihood in the physical frequency information between light and sound. The method of converting color image into sound was implemented by using HSI histograms through RGB-to-HSI color model conversion, which was done by Microsoft Visual C++ (ver. 6.0). Two different color images were used on the simulation experiments, and the results revealed that the hue, saturation and intensity elements of each input color image were converted into fundamental frequency, harmonic and octave elements of a sound, respectively. Through the proposed system, the converted sound elements were then synthesized to automatically generate a sound source with wav file format, using Csound.
