Author Full Names	Article Title	Author Keywords	Keywords Plus	Abstract
"Guenoun, Tamara; Tiberghien, Clementine; Vaillant-Juteau, Anne-Marie"	CARTOONS TO TRANSFORM THE SENSORY ATYPIA OF CHILDREN WITH AUTISM: THE THERAPEUTIC SETTING OF VIDEODRAMA	"autism spectrum disorder; video-based intervention; therapeutic mediation; play; sensoriality; narrativity"	SPECTRUM DISORDERS	Cartoons have been identified as a special interest for some children with ASD. This clinical finding was the starting point for the development of a therapeutic setting based on the slowed down viewing and replay of cartoons usually watched repetitively by these children with ASD. The method and the pluri-psychological approach between psychoanalysis and neuropsychology which served as a basis for reflection in the conception of this therapeutic program are presented successively. Two case-studies allow us to discuss the therapeutic modalities of this therapeutic setting, from the staging of the sensory atypia of the children, towards a symbolization of these psychic contents awaiting inscription with the shaping of a narrative structure for these children. The Videodrama highlights the importance of synesthetic telescopation of sensory canals in children with ASD, underlining certain particularities of their relationship to screens.
