"Jackson, Thomas E.; Sandramouli, Soupramanien"	Auditory-Olfactory Synesthesia Coexisting With Auditory-Visual Synesthesia		"COLORED-HEARING; SYNAESTHESIA"	Synesthesia is an unusual condition in which stimulation of one sensory modality causes an experience in another sensory modality or when a sensation in one sensory modality causes another sensation within the same modality. We describe a previously unreported association of auditory-olfactory synesthesia coexisting with auditoryvisual synesthesia. Given that many types of synesthesias involve vision, it is important that the clinician provide these patients with the necessary information and support that is available.
