"Nijboer, Tanja C. W.; Gebuis, Titia; Pas, Susan F. Te; van der Smagt, Maarten J."	Interactions between colour and synaesthetic colour: An effect of simultaneous colour contrast on synaesthetic colours	"Synaesthesia; Colour induction; Simultaneous colour contrast"	"SYNESTHESIA; NUMBERS; BRAIN"	We investigated whether simultaneous colour contrast affects the synaesthetic colour experience and normal colour percept in a similar manner. We simultaneously presented a target stimulus (i.e. grapheme) and a reference stimulus (i.e. hash). Either the grapheme or the hash was presented on a saturated background of the same or opposite colour category as the synaesthetic colour and the other stimulus on a grey background. In both conditions, grapheme-colour synaesthetes were asked to colour the hash in a colour similar to the synaesthetic colour of the grapheme. Controls that were pair-matched to the synaesthetes performed the same experiment, but for them, the grapheme was presented in the colour induced by the grapheme in synaesthetes. When graphemes were presented on a grey and the hash on a coloured background, a traditional simultaneous colour-contrast effect was found for controls as well as synaesthetes. When graphemes were presented on colour and the hash on grey, the controls again showed a traditional simultaneous colour-contrast effect, whereas the synaesthetes showed the opposite effect. Our results show that synaesthetic colour experiences differ from normal colour perception: both are susceptible to different surrounding colours, but not in a comparable manner. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
