"Ramachandran, Vilayanur S.; Seckel, Elizabeth"	Graphemes evoke synesthetic colors even before they are consciously recognized		"SYNAESTHESIA; PREVALENCE"	We showed a grapheme-color synesthete three different examples of stimuli in which the graphemes were 'hidden'-as in puzzle pictures-and became visible as letters only after prolonged viewing. Intriguingly the subject saw the appropriate colors accurately long before the graphemes became consciously visible-a novel form of blindsight.
