"Brang, David; Teuscher, Ursina; Ramachandran, V. S.; Coulson, Seana"	Temporal sequences, synesthetic mappings, and cultural biases: The geography of time	"Synesthesia; Synaesthesia; Time-space; Sequence-form; SNARC; Calendar; Spatial forms; Time forms"	"COLOR; SYNAESTHESIA; SPACE; EXPERIENCES; ASSOCIATIONS; METAPHORS; MIND"	Time-space synesthetes report that they experience the months of the year as having a spatial layout In Study 1, we characterize the phenomenology of calendar sequences produced by synesthetes and non-synesthetes, and show a conservative estimate of rime-space synesthesia at 22% of the population We demonstrate that synesthetes most commonly experience the months in a circular path. while non-synesthetes default to linear rows or rectangles. Study 2 compared synesthetes' and non-synesthetes' ability to memorize a novel spatial calendar, and revealed better performance in synesthetes The capacity to learn mappings between arbitrary spatial forms and temporal sequences is present in all individuals, and time-space synesthetes' enhanced visuo-spatial memory abilities may underlie their creation of idiosyncratic spatial calendar forms (C) 2010 Elsevier Inc All rights reserved
