Paz da Rosa, Fabio Jose	The Black Movement enunciated in corporealities, aesthetics and stories: synaesthetic constructions and reconstructions through the film Abolicao in the course of Pedagogy	"Decolonial Pedagogy; Black Movement; Synesthesias"		The present research aims to problematize the construction and reconstruction of imagery through the film Abolicao (1988), by Zozimo Bulbul, through the corporeal, aesthetic and historical categories enunciated by several characters from the Black Movement in a decolonial perspective and visual culture in the course of pedagogy from a state university located in Baixada Fluminense. For this purpose, we use the methodology of video installation, in order to relate the aesthetic and historical knowledge to the corporealities of the student-spectators. The result of the experience gave rise to synaesthetic practices that provided new reflections for the curriculum and didactics of the teacher training course, aimed at the redefinitions of Afro-Brazilian epistemologies
